nutrition.org.uk 2019-05-27

# Privacy Policy - British Nutrition Foundation

**Information we collect and how it is used**

The British Nutrition Foundation does not capture and store any personal information about individuals who access this web site, except (1) where you voluntarily choose to give us your personal details via email or the feedback form, or by enquiring about or ordering any of our services or publications; (2) register for an event; and/or (3), where you subscribe to one of our newsletters.

For publications, training and events, the data supplied is only used by BNF to process and fulfil the order (as it is a contract with BNF). Data is stored securely on [nutrition.org.uk](http://nutrition.org.uk/) and is accessed only by authorised BNF staff to process and fulfil the order. After two years, completed orders are deleted from nutrition.org.uk.  Data collected is not used for any other purpose than fulfilling the order received. BNF uses PayPal as its payment merchant. The privacy policy for PayPal can be found [here](https://www.paypal.com/en/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). 

When individuals register for BNF newsletters, the data supplied is only used by BNF to send specific newsletters, e.g. BNF News or BNF Education News. Newsletters contain information such as nutrition news and updates, education news, new or updated BNF resources, events and training opportunities. Individuals can view and update their information via a link in the newsletter email, as well as unsubscribe at any time. Registration for newsletters is via Your Mailing List Provider ([click here](https://www.ymlp.com/terms-of-service.html) for their terms of service and [data policy](https://www.ymlp.com/help.html?id=NjI1)).

We do not pass any of your personal information to outside organisations and/or individuals, except with your express consent (for example, if you register for BNF Healthy Eating Week and consent for your address to be used to send you posters). Data shared is encrypted. (For BNF Healthy Eating Week, registration is via Google Forms – [click here](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/compliance/#?modal_active=none) for their business and data compliance.)

The British Nutrition Foundation does not send cookies from this site and only monitors IP addresses of visitors to assess which pages are the most popular. Your IP address is automatically collected when you visit the site because your IP address needs to be recognised by the server. We use your IP address to record general site usage information and browsing preferences, but not to track your individual visit. We do not identify individual users in this sort of research. By using this website and by submitting information to us via this website you give your consent that any your personal data collected by us via this website (e.g. newsletter subscriptions and orders) may be processed by us for the purposes set out in this data privacy policy.

**Access your data**

You have a right to know about the personal information that the British Nutrition Foundation holds about you. You also have the right to have your data corrected or deleted.

If you have any questions about the use of your personal information, please contact the BNF at the address below. All requests will be acknowledged and processed within one month. This includes what data we hold, how it is used, amends and removal. BNF regularly deletes data which is no longer required.

If you require any further information about data protection and privacy rights in the UK, please visit [The Information Commissioner](https://ico.org.uk/) website.

**Cookies**

This website uses cookies, which are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. They cannot be used to get information from your computer about you or read any personal material kept by you on your computer. The cookie is used to make the link between you and the information you have provided to the website. The creation of a cookie on your computer does not give the website any access to other information such as your email address.

The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 (the Regulations) cover the use of cookies and similar technologies for storing information, and accessing information stored, on a user’s equipment such as their computer or mobile. Amendments to the regulations came into effect on 25 May 2011 The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011 make it compulsory for websites to inform users if cookies are being used, and to provide some information on how cookies are used.

You may delete and block all cookies from this site, but parts of the site will not work.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

**Disclaimer**

The information on this site is for your information only. We take every step to try and ensure that the information on the site is accurate and complete, but the BNF will not be responsible for any loss suffered or incurred as a result of any reliance placed on the site or its contents. The site contains links to other sites, but this is not an endorsement of the organisations they depict or their products or services. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for any of the material contained on any third party web site.

All material on this site is © British Nutrition Foundation 2018, unless otherwise stated. You may browse the site and print copies of extracts for personal use, but not for redistribution without our written consent.

The advice provided on this site is generic in nature. The British Nutrition Foundation cannot provide personalised dietary or lifestyle advice. If you require individually tailored advice regarding food, nutrition and lifestyle then contact your own GP or a dietitian.

**Contact information**

British Nutrition Foundation

New Derwent House

69-73 Theobalds Road

London

WC1X 8TA

Email: [[email protected]](https://www.nutrition.org.uk/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f68699858294998eb6988382849f829f9998d8998491d8839d)

Phone: 020 7557 7930

Web: [www.nutrition.org.uk](https://www.nutrition.org.uk/)  [www.foodafactoflife.org.uk](http://www.foodafactoflife.org.uk/)  [www.nutrition.training](http://www.nutrition.training/)

Registered charity No.251681

A charity registered in Scotland – SC040061 251681

Registered in England as a company limited by guarantee No. 898651

Note: Cookies on this site

****Cookie****

| 

****Name****

| 

****Purpose****

| 

****More Information****  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Session cookie

| 

Session cookie

| 

Stores user session. Session cookies allow users to be recognized within a website so any page changes or item or data selection you do is remembered from page to page. This cookie expires when you close your browser.  
  
Javascript enable cookie

| 

Has_js

| 

To check whether the user's browser supports JavaScript. This cookie expires when you close your browser.  
  
Site cookie acceptance

| 

cookiesDirective

| 

Used to prevent cookie popup from being displayed again to the same user.  
  
Site cookie acceptance

| 

cookiesAcceptance

| 

Used to store the user input on acceptance of cookie popup.  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

Session cookie

| 

Stores user session. Session cookies allow users to be recognized within a website so any page changes or item or data selection you do is remembered from page to page. This cookie expires when you close your browser.  
  
**Terms and Conditions Twitter giveaway March 2019**

  1. The competition is open to residents of the United Kingdom, excluding employees of British Nutrition Foundation and their close relatives and anyone otherwise connected with the organisation of the competition.
  2. There is no entry fee and no purchase necessary to enter this competition.
  3. Only one entry will be accepted per person. Multiple entries from the same person will be disqualified.
  4. The competition will be run on Twitter. The rules of the competition and how to enter are as follows:
  5. Entries must be made by re-tweeting and liking the Tweet and following @BNFEvents on Twitter.
  6. Closing date for entry will be 12pm on Friday 29th March 2019. After this date the no further entries to the competition will be permitted.
  7. The winner will be selected from all eligible entries received before the stated competition closing time. Entries received after the closing time will be invalid and will not be included in the competition.
  8. The prize is as follows: one hard copy of the BNF Task Force report _Cardiovascular Disease: Diet, Nutrition and Emerging Risk Factors, 2nd Edition_ ; 1 set of BNF 'Find your balance' resources comprising a poster, two booklets and a fridge magnet; 1 canvas _Food – a fact of life_ tote bag.
  9. The prize is as stated and no cash or other alternatives will be offered. The prize is not transferable.
  10. Winners will be chosen: at random by software, from all eligible entries received.
  11. The winner will be notified by tweet and by DM on Twitter within 28 days of the closing date.
  12. The winner agrees to the use of their twitter handle and image as well as their entry.
  13. If the winner cannot be contacted or do not claim the prize within 14 days of notification, we reserve the right to withdraw the prize from the winner and pick a replacement winner.
  14. BNF’s decision in respect of all matters to do with the competition will be final and no correspondence will be entered into.
